Abraham: Recently using personal
devices has become more commonplace
in working environments.
But it means that employees will hop
between corporate tools and personal
applications introducing several
risks associated with allowing
the use of personal devices in
conjunction with company networks.
Many companies have a BYOD policy
of 'bring your own device' to work,
which allows their employees to use
their own personal devices to save
time and money, as they are often
more productive than when using those
provided in the working environment.
Individuals are much more inclined to
update their devices more often and
keep all their apps and information up
to date in their own time, therefore,
saving time and money for the business.
However, businesses that let their
employees use their own personal
devices are at risk from data
theft, malware, legal problems
and lost and stolen devices.
It also makes it difficult in case there
is an incident in which the company
would have to take the personal device
off the employee to investigate, leading
to potentially embarrassing, whilst the
team conduct forensic investigations.
Employees should be fully aware
of any issues regarding the use of
personal devices regarding security
of data and responsibility for that.
Mobile security should be as
strong as network security, so as
not to put the company at risk.
The use of removable devices such as
laptops and tablets or even hard drives,
can cause conflicts when they are used for
personal reasons as well as for business.
This has become more of an
issue with remote working.
Company devices should be kept
strictly for work so as not to open
employees and business to conflict
of interest and security issues.
Also damage and theft as well as
misuse, that may open all parties
to legal issues with regards to
data protection and security, and
exposure to other cyber crimes.